<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-12T13:52:34+02:00</updated><id>https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">designing multispecies menstrual care 🌿🍷 project blog</title><subtitle>A project on designing sustainable menstrual care technologies.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Machine learning, mosses, and gynecology</title><link href="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/reflections/2021/04/12/machine-learning-mosses-gynecology.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Machine learning, mosses, and gynecology" /><published>2021-04-12T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-04-12T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/reflections/2021/04/12/machine-learning-mosses-gynecology</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/reflections/2021/04/12/machine-learning-mosses-gynecology.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/GyneGEN_gallery.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;GyneGAN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog entry is documenting early design explorations of how machine learning could be used to attend to more-than-human and multispecies menstrual care. ML and AI are not innocent technologies. Rather, as revealed by e.g. Kate Crawford and Joy Buolamwini, the material infrastructure of ML/AI are damaging the environment, and the embedded bias and logics are perpetuating social inequality through sexist and racist recommender and face recognition systems. By using ML in design explorations with menstrual care, I seek to both disentangle and grasp these politics and — if still possible — imagine feminist and more-than-human utopian uses and applications of ML for purposes that nurture both society and planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a three-day ML/AI workshop (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/auduno/aho-ml-workshop-v21&quot;&gt;https://github.com/auduno/aho-ml-workshop-v21&lt;/a&gt;), facilitated by Audun Mathias Øygard @auduno, I explored how machine learning could support the curiosities and entanglements that we are interesting in thickening in the multispecies menstrual care project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The machine learning tools include: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ml5js.org/&quot;&gt;ml5.js&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://teachablemachine.withgoogle.com/&quot;&gt;teachable machine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://runwayml.com/&quot;&gt;RunwayML&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artbreeder.com/browse&quot;&gt;Artbreeder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;moss-classifier&quot;&gt;Moss classifier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m building a moss classifier! A tool that can help you recognise and name specific moss species local to Stockholm. Looking through the camera, and with the support of a machine learning model, the moss classifier assists you to find that one specific moss — for instance sphagnum moss — which is great for menstrual products, or it accompanies you in discovering the multitude of mosses that make up the carpet of the forest, a revitalising activity of pure enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building the moss classifier entails several steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gathering mosses in forests around Stockholm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Training a machine learning model, through the teachable machine tool, to recognise and classify gathered mosses, through an image archive of mosses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designing the moss classifier interface and tool in ml5.js&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;padding:97.83% 0 0 0;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/535826376&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gynegan&quot;&gt;GyneGAN&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I trained a StyleGaN2 machine learning model on 914 images of gynecology tools from Norwegian museum archives (&lt;a href=&quot;http://digitaltmuseum.no&quot;&gt;digitaltmuseum.no&lt;/a&gt;) for 1999 steps in one hour with Runway ML. After that, I generated a latent walk video of the training model, which resulted in some creepy steel tools morphing into a car. The mesmerising slow aesthetics of these mundane yet anxiety-inducing tools perhaps tells us something about the violent and oppressive histories of gynaecology care as it has been performed on women, yet leaves it open how we could design care objects differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;padding:100% 0 0 0;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/534910928&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blood-moss&quot;&gt;Blood moss&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used Artbreeder to morph images of moss and blood into new constellations. This creative tool allows you to gain more control of the generated images by tuning different parametres in the StyleGEN2 model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/bloodmoss_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/bloodmoss_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These early examples seek to open new pathways for thinking-with machine learning systems in the context of multispecies menstrual care. It’s an exploration of using more-than-human imagination to ideate and visualise how menstrual care could be practiced in ways that nurture more-than the human body, for instance through the practice of gathering sphagnum moss for menstrual products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A remaining point for continuous reflection and critique is that ML models generate future images/decisions/predictions built on the past and that its planetary costs are high in terms of energy use and material resources. Could we, then, use ML to both tell the story of oppressive pasts as well as imagine more socially just futures? And could we both use AL systems of which planetary costs are high, to build and regenerate environmentally flourishing practices, rituals, tools or objects?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>by Marie Louise Juul Søndergaard</name></author><category term="reflections" /><summary type="html">GyneGAN This blog entry is documenting early design explorations of how machine learning could be used to attend to more-than-human and multispecies menstrual care. ML and AI are not innocent technologies. Rather, as revealed by e.g. Kate Crawford and Joy Buolamwini, the material infrastructure of ML/AI are damaging the environment, and the embedded bias and logics are perpetuating social inequality through sexist and racist recommender and face recognition systems. By using ML in design explorations with menstrual care, I seek to both disentangle and grasp these politics and — if still possible — imagine feminist and more-than-human utopian uses and applications of ML for purposes that nurture both society and planet.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">From biomaterials to compost</title><link href="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/reflections/2021/04/12/from-biomaterials-to-compost.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From biomaterials to compost" /><published>2021-04-12T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-04-12T10:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/reflections/2021/04/12/from-biomaterials-to-compost</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/reflections/2021/04/12/from-biomaterials-to-compost.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/process-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When mapping out the design space of this project I found it easier to define a few stages or steps in the lifecycle of imagined sustainable menstrual products. Our designs will address one or several stages of this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The process begins with the growth, gathering or harvesting of biomaterials, coming from plants, fungi, or other micro or nano structures. This stage might involve foraging for these materials in the forest, or growing them in a lab or at home. In this stage, designs might aid in this foraging, or the growing and nurturing of the living organisms.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The second stage involves turning these biomaterials into menstrual care artifacts or products, such as pads, tampons, wearable garments… or other objects that might support the menstrual cycle. Here designs could help menstruators fabricate their own products with biomaterials, or could speculate on how these products might look if fully organic.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The third phase is the use of the products during the bleeding phase of the menstrual cycle. Here our designs might aid in collecting or analyzing menstrual blood, understanding its components in terms of the body’s health and in terms of what contents might be nutritious for other species.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The final stage involves ‘disposing of’ the menstrual care products, either shredding or mixing the leftover organic materials with soil or compost, or diluting the blood with water or other nutritional components to be delivered as fertilizer for plants, or for the organic materials in the first stage. Here we could even imagine a cyclical process.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>by Nadia Campo Woytuk</name></author><category term="reflections" /><summary type="html">When mapping out the design space of this project I found it easier to define a few stages or steps in the lifecycle of imagined sustainable menstrual products. Our designs will address one or several stages of this process. The process begins with the growth, gathering or harvesting of biomaterials, coming from plants, fungi, or other micro or nano structures. This stage might involve foraging for these materials in the forest, or growing them in a lab or at home. In this stage, designs might aid in this foraging, or the growing and nurturing of the living organisms. The second stage involves turning these biomaterials into menstrual care artifacts or products, such as pads, tampons, wearable garments… or other objects that might support the menstrual cycle. Here designs could help menstruators fabricate their own products with biomaterials, or could speculate on how these products might look if fully organic. The third phase is the use of the products during the bleeding phase of the menstrual cycle. Here our designs might aid in collecting or analyzing menstrual blood, understanding its components in terms of the body’s health and in terms of what contents might be nutritious for other species. The final stage involves ‘disposing of’ the menstrual care products, either shredding or mixing the leftover organic materials with soil or compost, or diluting the blood with water or other nutritional components to be delivered as fertilizer for plants, or for the organic materials in the first stage. Here we could even imagine a cyclical process.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The use and scale of menstrual blood</title><link href="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/reflections/2021/03/29/the-use-and-scale.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The use and scale of menstrual blood" /><published>2021-03-29T10:50:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-03-29T10:50:00+02:00</updated><id>https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/reflections/2021/03/29/the-use-and-scale</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/reflections/2021/03/29/the-use-and-scale.html">&lt;p&gt;Potentially, menstrual blood can act as a fertilizer for plants, due to its rich nutrient composition. Although it has not been a subject of scientific and clinical trials, the practice of fertilizing houseplants and domestic gardens with menstrual blood is already widespread and &lt;a href=&quot;http://peer2pickle.weebly.com/menstrual-blood-fertilizer.html&quot;&gt;well documented on social media and blogs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when thinking at larger scales, at scales of mass production and consumption of plant-based food and products, of extensive crops and monoculture practices of modern-day agriculture, it’s hard to imagine that menstrual blood would be sufficient; it wouldn’t scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/pouringplant4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Fertilizing houseplants with menstrual blood diluted in water&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this way, the use of menstrual blood as a fertilizer only makes sense at local scales, where individuals are willing and are able to collect and distribute their blood to their houseplants, urban gardens or local wild flora.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Would the monthly blood of one menstruating human be enough to nourish the crops that this human, or a small collective, would consume during the month?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When giving a ‘practical use’ like fertilizer to menstrual blood, which is commonly considered waste, and ‘useless’, one could wonder if we might we be risking turning menstrual blood into a commodity. Imagine that menstrual blood is suddenly discovered to hold the miraculous properties of organic plant nutrition, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hudson.org.au/latest-news/womb-to-wounds-menstrual-fluid-could-repair-damaged-skin/&quot;&gt;reparation of wounded or damaged skin&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://we-make-money-not-art.com/whitefeather-hunter-the-witch-in-the-lab-coat/&quot;&gt;as a source of serum for nourishing tissue culture and possibly lab-grown meat&lt;/a&gt;… Wouldn’t it suddenly be regarded as liquid gold?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/mooncalf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitefeatherhunter.ca/new-research&quot; class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;WhiteFeather Hunter, Mooncalf, 2019-present&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait, menstrual blood can already do all that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. Yet menstrual blood has not been harvested and packaged away by trendy silicon-valley startups, and we are yet to imagine what a multinational-pharmaceutical-company-owned menstrual blood bank would look like. This is possibly because menstrual blood carries the enormous weight of centuries of stigma, disgust and shame. The menstrual products that currently exist in the world build on this stigma, and more broadly, on the objectification and control of marginalized bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not arguing for the commodification of menstrual blood here; quite the opposite. I am arguing that the practices of collecting, understanding, noticing and nourishing other species with menstrual blood are acts of defiance of a capitalist system, they do not fit within a system that oppresses and enforces stigmas upon menstruating bodies. Menstrual blood as ‘useful’ doesn’t fit into capitalist dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, it will be necessary to hold on to these reflections and keep them in mind when further in the design process. If we are not interested in scaling the use of menstrual blood, but focusing on local and communal practices, it is essential to consider designing a &lt;strong&gt;process or ritual&lt;/strong&gt; rather than a &lt;strong&gt;product&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.missingwitches.com/2019/10/23/witches-found-whitefeather-hunter/&quot;&gt;The making is not less important than what is made&lt;/a&gt;, and in this case, the making, the exploration of the materiality of menstrual blood, is what could be truly radical.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>by Nadia Campo Woytuk</name></author><category term="reflections" /><summary type="html">Potentially, menstrual blood can act as a fertilizer for plants, due to its rich nutrient composition. Although it has not been a subject of scientific and clinical trials, the practice of fertilizing houseplants and domestic gardens with menstrual blood is already widespread and well documented on social media and blogs. However, when thinking at larger scales, at scales of mass production and consumption of plant-based food and products, of extensive crops and monoculture practices of modern-day agriculture, it’s hard to imagine that menstrual blood would be sufficient; it wouldn’t scale. Fertilizing houseplants with menstrual blood diluted in water</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Material exploration: Sphagnum moss</title><link href="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/material/2021/03/18/moss.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Material exploration: Sphagnum moss" /><published>2021-03-18T10:23:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-18T10:23:00+01:00</updated><id>https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/material/2021/03/18/moss</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/material/2021/03/18/moss.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog entry will be a ‘living’ description on explorations with Sphagnum moss, updated as material explorations progress.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last fall, my friend, collaborator and moss-lover Marie Louise Juul Søndergaard introduced me to the curious connections of moss and menstruation. Many of the ideas and explorations in this entry build on our conversations and shared experiments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/IMG_1242.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sphagnum&lt;/em&gt; moss, also known as ‘peat moss’, is a variety of mosses that can hold large quantities of water inside its cells, up to 25 times its dry weight, and it can be found all over Sweden [&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gbif.org/species/144105015&quot;&gt;Global Biodiversity Information Facility&lt;/a&gt;]. Because of its highly absorbent and antiseptic properties, Sphagnum moss is used as a soil conditioner in gardening, and, curiously enough, it has also been used throughout history to absorb bodily fluids. This moss has been used in many indigenous cultures as a lining and ‘disposable diaper’ for infant’s cradles, or in western culture, for dressing wounds during the World Wars [&lt;em&gt;Robin Wall Kimmerer, 2003. Gathering moss: a natural and cultural history of mosses&lt;/em&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, it is not surprising to find instances of the use of this moss for collecting menstrual blood, and even manufactured examples, such as a moss-filled sanitary pads that briefly circulated in the USA during 1919, named ‘Sfag-na-kins’ [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mum.org/sfagnak.htm&quot;&gt;SFAG-NA-KINS menstrual pad box and ads&lt;/a&gt;]. The feasibility and implications for both the environment and women’s health for using Sphagnum moss as a material for menstrual products are extremely positive [&lt;em&gt;Tracy E Roe. Sustainability, menstrual products and sphagnum moss : An investigation&lt;/em&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/IMG_1420.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
I have tried drying sphagnum moss Marie Louise and I harvested from a forest in Stockholm last fall. I used a bamboo herb drying structure I purchased here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robygge.se/hus-hem/orttork-torkolla-robygge/&quot;&gt;Örttork - Torkolla, Robygge - Hus &amp;amp; Hem - Robygge.se&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accumulations of Sphagnum can store water, since both living and dead plants can hold large quantities of water inside their cells; plants may hold 16 to 26 times as much water as their dry weight, depending on the species.&lt;/em&gt; From &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sphagnum&quot;&gt;Sphagnum - Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/sphagnum-cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/wildlifetrusts_40330515945.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/21629_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Microscopic Life in Sphagnum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sphagnum moss is often used in crafting and gardening as a planting medium (for example, for orchids), for lining baskets, for seed starting, or for decorative purposes, such as the Japanese moss balls called &lt;em&gt;kokedama&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/kokedama%20jpg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.residencemagazine.se/diy/diy-hang-upp-vaxterna-sa-gor-du-en-kokedama/3795003&quot;&gt;DIY: Häng upp växterna – så gör du en kokedama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;knitting-sphagnum&quot;&gt;Knitting Sphagnum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an initial design experiment, I have attempted to knit my dried sphagnum between layers of cotton (this could be another biodegradable yarn instead). The texture of the dried moss is very powdery —it disintegrates quickly, and therefore it might be the best kind of material to spin into fibers, or to put in direct contact with intimate areas.
These kid of patches could later be incorporated into pouches or pockets of fabric, similar to the SFAG-NA-KINS, which would be much more comfortable against the skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dried moss can be regrown later by just adding water. Perhaps the nutrients in menstrual blood, acting as a fertilizer, could contribute to the growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/IMG_3983.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/IMG_3986.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;compressed-sphagnum&quot;&gt;Compressed sphagnum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moss blocks can be purchased in gardening stores, and are often used to retain moisture in potted plants. Perhaps one could imagine a tampon made from one of these moss blocks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/2749_2955_large.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>by Nadia Campo Woytuk</name></author><category term="material" /><summary type="html">This blog entry will be a ‘living’ description on explorations with Sphagnum moss, updated as material explorations progress. Last fall, my friend, collaborator and moss-lover Marie Louise Juul Søndergaard introduced me to the curious connections of moss and menstruation. Many of the ideas and explorations in this entry build on our conversations and shared experiments.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">first blog entry: designing multispecies menstrual care project</title><link href="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/update/2021/03/15/first-entry.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="first blog entry: designing multispecies menstrual care project" /><published>2021-03-15T13:41:28+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-15T13:41:28+01:00</updated><id>https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/update/2021/03/15/first-entry</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/update/2021/03/15/first-entry.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/pouringblood.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m opening up a blog for the project ‘Designing Multispecies Menstrual Care’, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kth.se/sv/navet/research/projects/designing-multispecies-menstrual-care-1.1040991&quot;&gt;a NAVET collaboration between KTH and Konstfack&lt;/a&gt;. In this project we will explore the design of menstrual management technologies and services, focusing on different aspects of the experience of menstruation: the assembly and design of the products, the use, and the waste and composting of the organic materials leftover from the process. &lt;!--more--&gt; This will result in a design proposal and a high fidelity prototype which could be a smart wearable garment produced with biobased materials, or a physical device, such as a waste bin, which enables the collection, analysis, and compost of the bodily fluids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog I will describe the design process, including reflections, experiments and random thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>by Nadia Campo Woytuk</name></author><category term="update" /><summary type="html">I’m opening up a blog for the project ‘Designing Multispecies Menstrual Care’, a NAVET collaboration between KTH and Konstfack. In this project we will explore the design of menstrual management technologies and services, focusing on different aspects of the experience of menstruation: the assembly and design of the products, the use, and the waste and composting of the organic materials leftover from the process.</summary></entry></feed>