<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-03-16T10:39:23+01:00</updated><id>https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">designing multispecies menstrual care - project blog</title><subtitle>A project on designing sustainable menstrual care technologies.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">first blog entry: designing multispecies menstrual care project</title><link href="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/update/2021/03/15/first-entry.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="first blog entry: designing multispecies menstrual care project" /><published>2021-03-15T14:41:28+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-15T14:41:28+01:00</updated><id>https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/update/2021/03/15/first-entry</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nadiacw.github.io//menstrual-care-blog/update/2021/03/15/first-entry.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/menstrual-care-blog/assets/images/pouringblood.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m opening up a blog for the project ‘Designing Multispecies Menstrual Care’, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kth.se/sv/navet/research/projects/designing-multispecies-menstrual-care-1.1040991&quot;&gt;a NAVET collaboration between KTH and Konstfack&lt;/a&gt;. In this project we will explore the design of menstrual management technologies and services, focusing on different aspects of the experience of menstruation: the assembly and design of the products, the use, and the waste and composting of the organic materials leftover from the process. &lt;!--more--&gt; This will result in a design proposal and a high fidelity prototype which could be a smart wearable garment produced with biobased materials, or a physical device, such as a waste bin, which enables the collection, analysis, and compost of the bodily fluids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog I will describe the design process, including reflections, experiments and random thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="update" /><summary type="html">I’m opening up a blog for the project ‘Designing Multispecies Menstrual Care’, a NAVET collaboration between KTH and Konstfack. In this project we will explore the design of menstrual management technologies and services, focusing on different aspects of the experience of menstruation: the assembly and design of the products, the use, and the waste and composting of the organic materials leftover from the process.</summary></entry></feed>